pollingpoint.com 2004-10-14

# Privacy Policy

The information you give us is absolutely confidential. As a respondent you are safe.

We will never disclose your personal information to anyone at any time.

We urge you to read this Privacy Policy carefully.

We have organized this Privacy Policy under the following topics: 

**ARTICLE 1:**Our Accreditation and Privacy Seals

**ARTICLE 2:**About This Privacy Policy and Using Our Site

**ARTICLE 3:**Non-Personal Information We Collect About You

  * Cookies 
  * Web Beacons 

**ARTICLE 4:**Personally Identifiable Information We Collect About You

  * E-mails you send to PollingPoint
  * Survey Information

**ARTICLE 5:**PollingPoint Use

  * Concept Unique Identifiers
  * Aggregate Data
  * Secure Message Center

**ARTICLE 6:**Disclosure of Your Information

  * Disclosure to Website Service and Content Contractors
  * Disclosure of Aggregate Information

**ARTICLE 7:**How PollingPoint Handles Privacy and Security Internally

**ARTICLE 8:**Contacting PollingPoint

  * Removing your Personally Identifiable Information
  * Limitations on Removing or Changing Information
  * Complaints

**ARTICLE 9:**Changes to this Privacy Policy

**ARTICLE 10:**Glossary

## ARTICLE 1: OUR ACCREDITATION AND PRIVACY SEALS

To provide you confidence that we adhere to accepted industry privacy standards we will inform you of the following in this Privacy Policy: 

  * What personally identifiable information of yours is collected;
  * What organization is collecting the information; 
  * How the information is used; 
  * With whom the information may be shared; 
  * What choices are available regarding collection, use and distribution of the information; 
  * What kind of security procedures are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control; and
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

## ARTICLE 2: ABOUT THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND USING OUR SITE

This Privacy Policy applies to the PollingPoint website.

We hope that reading our Privacy Policy gives you a clear idea of how we manage information about you. Throughout our Privacy Policy, we have underlined various terms and hot-linked them to our Glossary or to the corresponding section within the Privacy Policy to help you better understand their meaning.

We may collect Non-Personal Information through the use of Cookies or Web Beacons.

## ARTICLE 3: NON-PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU

We may collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our website.

**A. Cookies**

We collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our website through the use of Cookies. Every computer is assigned a different Cookie by PollingPoint. The information collected by Cookies allows us to:

  * Statistically monitor how many people are using our website;
  * Monitor how many people open our e-mails; and
  * Determine for what purposes these actions are being taken.

Cookies are also used to facilitate a user's log-in, as navigation aides and as session timers, but not to retain Personal Information about you. Cookies used by PollingPoint are also used to restrict underage use of the tools. Your browser software can be set to reject all Cookies. Most browsers offer instructions on how to reset the browser to reject Cookies in the "Help" section of the toolbar. If you reject our Cookies, certain functions and conveniences of our website may not work properly, but you do not have to accept our Cookies in order to use our site. We do not link Non-Personal Information from Cookies to Personally Identifiable Information without your permission, and do not use Cookies to collect or store Personal Information about you. 

**B. Web Beacons**

We also may use Web Beacons, to collect Non-Personal Information about your use of our website. The information collected by Web Beacons (i) allows us to statistically monitor how many people are using our website, (ii) how many people open our e-mails, and (iii) for what purposes these actions are being taken. Our Web Beacons are not used to track your activity outside of our websites. We do not link Non-Personal Information from Web Beacons to Personally Identifiable Information without your permission and do not use Web Beacons to collect or store Personal Information about you.

## ARTICLE 4: PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU 

**A. E-mails You Send to PollingPoint**

This Privacy Policy does not protect you when you send content, business information, ideas, concepts or inventions to PollingPoint by e-mail. If you want to keep content or business information, ideas, concepts or inventions private or proprietary, do not send them in an e-mail to PollingPoint. We try to answer every e-mail within 48 business hours, but are not always able to do so.

**B. Children**

We are committed to protecting the privacy of children. Neither PollingPoint nor any of its services are designed or intended to attract children under the age of 18. We do not collect Personally Identifiable Information from any person we actually know is under the age of 18.

**C. Survey Information**

When participating in a survey, we may ask you to submit Personally Identifiable Information. This Personally Identifiable Information is used for research purposes, and is not used for sales solicitations. When a survey is sponsored by a third party, Aggregate Information of the survey results is reported to the sponsor. Personally Identifiable Information collected through surveys will be used only by PollingPoint and its operations contractors, and will not be given or sold to a third party without your consent. In the course of collecting survey responses from our members, we may use Cookies to authenticate respondents or to help you pick up where you left off in a survey. If you have Cookies disabled you may not be able to participate in some studies. Cookies may be used to connect survey data with PollingPoint site usage characteristics. You will be notified when we would like to use Cookies in this way and your consent will be requested for these Cookies.

## ARTICLE 5: POLLINGPOINT USE 

**Aggregate Data**

PollingPoint may combine, in a non-identifiable format, the Personal Information you provide with information from other users to create Aggregate Data that may be disclosed to third parties. Aggregate data does not contain any information that could be used to contact or identify you. For example, PollingPoint may use information gathered to create a composite profile of all the viewers of a particular television show. PollingPoint will not disclose your personally identifiable information to any third party without your prior permission. 

## ARTICLE 6: DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION 

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, PollingPoint will not disclose any Personally Identifiable or Personal information it gathers from you on our website. We will only release Personally Identifiable or Personal information to third parties: (1) to comply with valid legal requirements such as a law, regulation, search warrant, subpoena or court order; or (2) in special cases, such as a physical threat to you or others. In the event that we are legally compelled to disclose your Personally Identifiable or Personal information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or court order. In addition, we may disclose Personal Information as described below. 

**A. Disclosure to PollingPoint Operations and Maintenance Contractors**

PollingPoint operations and maintenance contractors sometimes have limited access to your Personally Identifiable Information in the course of providing products or services to PollingPoint. These contractors include vendors and suppliers that provide us with technology, services, and/or content related to better operation and maintenance of our website. Access to your Personally Identifiable Information by these contractors is limited to the information reasonably necessary for the contractor to perform its limited function for PollingPoint. We also contractually require that our operations and maintenance contractors 1) protect the privacy of your Personally Identifiable Information consistent with this Privacy Policy, and 2) not use or disclose your Personally Identifiable Information for any purpose other than providing us with products and services.

**B. Disclosure of Aggregate Information**

PollingPoint may provide Aggregate Information to third parties. For example, we might inform third parties regarding the number of users of our website and the activities they conduct while on our site. We might also inform an interested policy group that "30% of our users live east of the Mississippi" or that "25% of our users have registered to vote online." Depending on the circumstances, we may or may not charge third parties for this Aggregate Information. We require parties with whom we share Aggregate Information to agree that they will not attempt to make this information personally identifiable, such as by combining it with other databases.

## ARTICLE 7: HOW POLLINGPOINT HANDLES PRIVACY AND SECURITY INTERNALLY 

**Listed below are some of the security procedures that PollingPoint uses to protect your privacy:**

  * Uses firewalls to protect information held in our servers. 
  * Utilizes Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption in transmitting Personally Identifiable Information to our servers. In order to take advantage of encryption technology, you must have an Internet browser which supports 128-bit encryption. 
  * Requires all PollingPoint employees to abide by our Privacy Policy and be subject to disciplinary action if they violate it.
  * Backs-up our systems to protect the integrity of your Personally Identifiable and Personal information.

**PollingPoint provides additional protection for your Personal information as follows:**

  * Provides passcode protection of PollingPoint servers and limits access to these servers.  The server site maintains physical security through pass code locked door access and pass code authority.
  * Limits access to Personally Identifiable Information to authorized users. PollingPoint enables you to have full control over who has access to your Personal information.

Despite PollingPoint's best efforts to protect your Personally Identifiable Information and Personal information, there is always some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way around our security systems or that transmissions of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. However, PollingPoint will always be vigilant in minimizing such risk to the best of our ability.

## ARTICLE 8: CONTACTING POLLINGPOINT 

**Complaints**

If you have a complaint or problem, please e-mail us at help@pollingpoint.com.

Our customer service department will forward your complaint to the appropriate internal PollingPoint department for a response or resolution. We try to answer every e-mail within 48 business hours, but we may not always be able to do so.

If you do not receive adequate resolution of a privacy related problem, you may write to PollingPoint's Privacy Help Desk at: 

PollingPoint,Inc.  
364 University Ave   
Palo Alto, CA 94301

**Limitations on Removing or Changing Information**

Upon your request, we will delete your Personally Identifiable or Personal Information from our active databases and where feasible from our back-up media. You should be aware that it is not technologically possible to remove each and every record of the information you have provided to PollingPoint from our servers.

## ARTICLE 9: CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY 

**Personally Identifiable Information**

We will inform you if a material change to the Privacy Policy is made that involves the use of your Personally Identifiable Information. Your continued use of the PollingPoint website will indicate acceptance of the changes. You may of course choose to Opt-out of continuing to use the website. Please exit the site immediately if you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy or any revised policy. 

**Personal information**

We will inform you if a material change in the Privacy Policy is made that involves the use of your Personal information, and your express Opt-in authorization will be requested. If you choose to not accept the new privacy policy, then the current privacy policy conditions will remain in effect, so long as PollingPoint continues to make the functionality available. PollingPoint reserves the right to discontinue or limit functionality in all its products. 

## ARTICLE 10: GLOSSARY 

**Aggregate Information or Data** : As a website gathers individual pieces of Non-Personal Information (see definition below) from its users, it may combine similar data from many or all the users of the website into one big "batch". For example, the site may add up the total number of people in Peoria, Illinois, (but not their names) who are seeking information about weight loss and compare that to the number of people in Petaluma, California seeking the same information. 

This sort of statistical information is called aggregate data because it reflects the habits and characteristics of a large group of anonymous people. Websites may use aggregate data or share it with their business partners so that the information and services they provide best meet the needs of the users. Aggregate data also helps advertisers and sponsors on the Web know how effectively they are reaching and meeting the needs of their target audience.

**Browser** : Short for web browser, a browser is software application used to locate and display web (Internet) pages. The three most popular browsers are AOL, Microsoft Internet Explorer, and Netscape Navigator. In addition, most modern browsers can present multimedia information, including sound and video, though they require plug-ins for some formats.

**Cache** (also called cache memory): Once your web browser accesses a web page, it references that page and the graphics on it within your computer's "cache" (or more simply, your computer takes a "snapshot" of every page you visit and stores it in the "cache".) The next time you visit that same page, your download time will be quicker as the images and much of the page is already available on your computer for your browser to reference instantly instead of waiting for the page and images to download again. PollingPoint does not cache pages. 

**Click Stream Information** :A record of all the pages you have visited during your visit to a particular website or the services you accessed from the site or from an email. Click Stream Information is associated with your browser and not with you personally. It records the archives of your browser. 

**Cookie** : A small data file that is stored on the hard drive of the computer you use to view a website. Cookies are placed by that site or by a third party with a presence on the site, such as an advertiser using a Web Beacon (see definition below) and are accessible only by the party or site that placed the Cookie (i.e. a Cookie placed on your computer by PollingPoint isn't accessed by any other site you visit but a Cookie placed on your computer by an advertiser may be accessed by any site on which that same advertiser has a presence). Cookies can contain pieces of  Personally Identifiable Information (PII). PollingPoint encrypts any PII it stores in its Cookies. These Cookies often are used to make the site easier to use. For example, if you check a box to ask that we store your user name on your computer so that you don't have to enter it each time you visit the site, it's stored in a Cookie on your computer.

**Encryption** : The translation of data into a secret code. Encryption is the most effective way to achieve data security. To read an encrypted file, you must have access to a secret key or password that enables you to decrypt it. This is typically done by secure computer systems. 

**Firewall** : A system designed to prevent unauthorized access to or from a public or private network. Firewalls can be implemented in both hardware and software, or a combination of both. Firewalls are frequently used to prevent unauthorized Internet users from accessing private portions of public networks. All messages entering or leaving the network pass through the firewall, which examines each message and blocks those that do not meet the specified security criteria. 

**Non-Personal Information** : Information that is not traceable back to any individual and cannot be used to identify an individual. For example, Click Stream Information is Non-Personal Information, as is information such as gender, age, city and state when not linked with other Personally Identifiable Information.

**Opt-In** : Means you are actively indicating your preference to participate in a program, email, feature, tool, or enhancement on a website. Typically, if you "Opt-in" you must provide certain information, usually Personally Identifiable Information, to the website or otherwise actively indicate your choice or preference to participate in the website program. 

**Opt-Out** : Means that if you do not take some action you are indicating your preference to participate in a program, email, feature, tool or enhancement on a website. Typically, if you "Opt-out" you must uncheck a box next to a stated preference or otherwise take some indicate action to indicate your preference not to participate ina program. For example, if you do not wish to receive promotional emails from PollingPoint or its sponsors, you must uncheck the box in your email preference center that states: "Please send me special offers and communications from PollingPoint and/or its partners that would interest me." 

**Password** : A secret series of characters, typically alphanumeric (meaning it consists of both letters and numbers) that enables a user to access a file, computer, or program. The user must enter his or her password before the computer or system will respond to commands. The password helps ensure that unauthorized users do not access the system.In addition, data files and programs may require a password. 

Ideally, the password should be something that nobody could guess. In practice, many people choose a password that is easy to remember, such as their name or their initials. This is one reason it is relatively easy to break into many computer systems. 

**Personally Identifiable Information (PII)(also called Personal Information)** : Information that can be traced back to an individual (contrast with Non-Personal Information and Aggregate Information). Examples of PII include your name, home address, telephone number, email address, and Social Security number. 

If other pieces of information are linked to PII, they also become PII. For example, if you use a nickname to chat online and give out your real name while chatting, your nickname becomes PII when linked with other PII.

**Server** : A computer that provides services to other computers. A "web server" stores web site files and "serves" them to people who request them. 

**SSL** (Secure Sockets Layer): A security protocol developed by Netscape for transmitting private information via the Internet. SSL works by using a private key to encrypt data that's transferred over the SSL connection. Both Microsoft Internet Explorer (http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/S/Internet_Explorer.htm) and Netscape Navigator (http://www.webopedia.com/TERM/S/Navigator.htm) support SSL, and many Web sites use the protocol to obtain confidential user information, such as credit card numbers. By convention, URLs that utilize an SSL connection start with https: instead of http. 

**Username** : A name used to gain access to a computer system or program. Usernames, and often passwords, are required in shared systems, such as the Internet. In most such systems, users can choose their own usernames and passwords. 

Usernames are also required to access some bulletin board and online services such as PollingPoint.

**Virus** : A program or piece of code that is loaded onto your computer without your knowledge and runs against your wishes. Viruses can also "replicate" themselves by copying their code to other computers. All computer viruses are manmade. A simple virus that can make a copy of itself over and over again is relatively easy to produce. Even such a simple virus is dangerous because it will quickly use all available memory and bring the system to a halt. An even more dangerous type of virus is one capable of transmitting itself across networks and bypassing security systems. There are numerous virus protection programs vailable. See the "How You Can Protect Yourself" section.

**Web Beacons** (also often referenced as "clear GIFs", "web bugs", "1-by-1 GIFs", "Single-Pixal GIFs", "1 x 1 Pixals", or "clear Pixals"): Tiny graphic image files, imbedded in a web page in GIF, jpeg or HTML format, that provide a presence on the web page and send back to its home server (which can belong to the host site, a network advertiser or some other third party) information from the Users' browser, such as the IP address, the URL of the page on which the beacon is located, the type browser that is accessing the site and the ID number of any Cookies on the Users' computer previously placed by that server. Web Beacons can also be used to place a Cookie on the Users' browser.
